-CHORUS SINGS:
♪ The Simpsons ♪
-(chuckling)
D'oh!
(tires screeching)
(grunts)
(panting)
(growling)
(barking)
♪♪
NED:
Thank you all for coming.
Now. let's start with the words
everyone loves to hear:
"Welcome to Bible study!"
Today. my readin'
ribbon's smack-dab
in the middle
of Matthew 23.
Now let us download
the holy tweet of the Lord.
Stop making this relatable.
Hey. as a youth.
if I don't hear a computer word
every couple sentences.
I am outta here.
Duly noted.
But we will make sure
not to dilute the sacred gospel.
Mouse pad!
Double click! Skype!
Skype!
(clears throat)
Matthew 23:
"Then spake Jesus
to the multitude.
and to his disciples. saying..."
HOMER:
Hey. my bathing suit came off!
Whoo!
Whoa!
Hey. it floats!
(sighs)
I'll handle this.
Schnell! Schnell!
-(ringing)
-(Homer cheering)
(groans)
Homer Simpson.
You are the most infuriating.
Netflix DVD-burglaring.
barbecue-not-putting-out...
(hooting)
...man I ever met!
Hold that thought.
Oh!
That man is beyond
redemption.
That might seem
to be true...
I sense a "but"
coming. Reverend...
HOMER:
Here comes the butt!
But I think you're up
to the challenge. Ned.
Oh. Reverend. I've been working
my Bible to the bone
trying to save that man.
You know. Ned. God has never
given up on anyone.
What about Sodom
and Gomorrah?
He lovingly
destroyed them.
Instead of
pushing Homer away.
can't you find a way
to reach out and bring him in?
(chanting)
(sighs)
Homer?
(clears throat)
You know. our Bible study group
is going
to the Holy Land next month.
I'd like you and your family
to come as my guests.
Hmm. let me think...
Take my family to a war zone
on a bus filled
with religious lame-os
in a country with no pork
in a desert with no casinos...
Ooh. where do I sign up?
Homer. I can hear your sarcasm
from inside the house.
And the dishwasher's on!
What's going on here?
Mr. Flanders
invited us to Israel.
I think he wants
to get Dad into Heaven.
-Great. More hell for me.
-(Bart and Homer laugh)
Ned Flanders. you would take
our family to the Holy Land
just to try to make my husband
a better man?
Yep. I also want to try
something called "pita bread."
Well. we will take you up
on your offer.
Oh...
But we insist on
paying our own way.
Oh!
And Homer. put
on some pants.
(screaming)
Oh!
The man hates pants.
♪♪
(glass shatters)
ALL:
L'chaim!
Homie. just tell them
what they want to hear.
I can't!
Latkes aren't as good
as American pancakes.
(groans)
They're okay with applesauce.
True enough.
(grunts)
A truckload of applesauce!
Eh...
Krusty. I've been
meaning to ask.
What are you doing
on this tour?
I believe that every Jew
should make a pilgrimage
to Israel before he dies.
Yes. it is fitting.
(laughs)
Don't want to end up in hell.
Jews don't
believe in hell.
No hell?
Thank you. kid.
You made my day.
(vocalizing)
(fiddle playing)
You're being paid
to clean the gutters!
This country's so historic.
For all we know. Jesus
could have given a talk
in Conference Room C.
MAN:
Welcome. welcome!
-Hey.
My name is Jacob.
You may notice I speak the
English with a slight accent.
This is because. as you
have probably guessed.
I used to live in London.
and that is why I sound
like Hugh Grant.
Come on. Let's go.
We've got a lot of holy
sites to see. Yallah!
We finish early.
we go to jewelry store
owned by my cousins.
(all laughing)
No joke. Is true.
Great prices.
You got to haggle. Otherwise
they don't respect you!
Come on. Let's go!
Do you have any safety tips?
What are you talking about?
Israel is the safest country
in the world.
The only danger here
is dehydration.
Drink water.
Don't die. Looks bad on me.
Come on. Shut your face.
Let's go.
But it says here
in the brochure...
Brochure? Brochure?
Brochure?
Who wrote your brochure?
The same schmuck
who wrote the New Testament?
I can't talk to you.
You talk to my
niece. Doreet.
Doreet. talk
to the stupids.
Shalom. goyim!
Shalom to you!
Shalom is the "aloha"
of this place.
Okay. okay. lady.
You done talking now?
Who is licensed tour guide here.
you or me?
Now. everybody. we have
no time to see Masada.
Everybody died
there for nothing.
Okay. first stop:
Old City.
Come on. Let's go.
Please. shut your face!
(gasps):
The Old City.
Where B.C. turned
into A.D.! Let's go!
Flanders. that stuff's been here
for thousands of years.
But the breakfast buffet
at this hotel.
which is included
in our package.
closes in ten minutes!
Homer. that's not
why we're here.
We can see the stations
of the cross.
After we see the stations
of the omelet bar.
(groans)
Okay. let's just
put it to a vote.
I can't believe
we lost. Reverend.
Mm-hmm.
These blueberry
muffins are bigger
than the ones we
had at Pechanga.
Finally. something you like
better than Pechanga.
♪♪
Okay. everybody. Please
shut your face. Here we go.
This sacred spot on Mount Zion
is King David's tomb.
Also. where your Jesus.
who was a native-born Israeli.
by the way--
sandals. circumcised.
perfect English accent.
the whole deal...
This is where
he had his last supper
before they took him away
and hammered him up
on that cross.
(laughing)
Hey. you. You're not part
of the group. No listening!
What? Is Israel.
Is free country.
(yelling in Hebrew)
(bleep)
(continues yelling in Hebrew)
Okay. that's it.
Because of him.
no Armenian quarter.
Forget it. It's gone.
All thanks to
Mr. Listen-for-Free.
Lord. please help Homer
experience the redemptive power
of this sacred land.
(gasps) He's going
for the record.
He's going
for the record!
(groans)
Flanders. you're not supposed
to help him.
Yeah. thanks a lot. Flanders.
(sighs)
Homer. do you think
you could show
just the slightest bit
of reverence?
Ned. I'm an
American tourist.
I'm just here to see some
sights. try goofy new food
and spread some shekels with my
Carolina Panthers credit card.
Panthers!
(sighs) Homer. could you at
least turn the camera off?
If you say it
like Dracula. I will.
-Homer...
-Please. please. please...
Bleh!
(laughing)
That is going right
on StupidFlanders.org.
You know. Homer.
you might really benefit
from opening your heart to
the spirituality of this place.
Please. neighbor?
This really means
a lot to you. huh?
Yes. but it
means more to you.
Boy. are you lousy
at reading minds.
Okay. okay.
For you. I'll try.
FLANDERS:
Lord. I think I may
have finally reached him.
FLANDERS (on recording):
Bleh! Bleh! Bleh!
Homer. quit
playing that back.
I'm not. It's
my ring tone.
Yello.
This is he.
Yeah. I wanted to know:
do you deliver falafels
to the top of Mount Zion?
Great. I'd like
a large falafel
with pepperoni. sausage.
and extra cheese.
Yes. I know
what a falafel is.
(sighs)
This. eh... Everybody.
look at my face.
This is the Western. or
as you say. Wailing Wall.
It is believed that the Lord
will grant the prayers
that are stuck into the cracks.
Please. no graffiti.
no making the pishen. Yallah.
"Dear Lord: please fix the
following parking tickets:
A647253.
SP90325.
Shelbyville 932871..."
Sad.
Never gonna happen.
Maybe. if you were Brad Pitt.
Hey. boy. we're supposed
to be acting religiousy.
What are you up to?
Reading prayers and
ignoring them. just like God.
Hey. this one's from you.
"Dear Lord.
don't let Marge find out
the hotel leaves chocolates
on the pillows at night."
Why. you little...
(choking)
"Give my dad
another heart attack?"
(shouts)
Smite him like
the firstborn of Egypt.
Dead baby. dead baby. Passover.
dead baby. dead baby...
(chicken clucks)
(man crying prayer call)
Hey. why am I
running from a girl?
Call me when you're old enough
for your bat mitzvah.
I'll bring you an envelope
full of nothin'.
(grunts)
Karate!
Krav maga!
Krav ma-wha?
Israeli karate.
Less hyah.
more hyah
ha-mee-ha-gee!
(grunts)
(grunting)
You don't fight like a girl.
Or even a Milhouse.
I don't know what is
"Milhouse."
(grunting)
I work security
for the tour.
Dealing with American
punks like you
counts as my
military service.
And we know
all about you.
BART:  Ay. caramba.
Hey. is that
the Ark of the Covenant?
(grunting)
Karate!
Once again. Krav maga!
(grunting)
Quit going for my groin!
No groin. no Krav maga.
(grunting in pain)
Hello. groin.
(speaks Hebrew)
Come on. come on!
Everybody finish lemon ice--
not allowed inside.
Before us stands the Church
of the Holy Sepulchre.
believed to be the home
of the tomb of your Lord.
Or as he's known here.
"the man in the underpants."
Beautiful tachtoonim.
Oh. and what abs!
He was a real good-looking one.
Nice hair. Conditioner?
I think so.
And. Lord. thank you
for letting me see
this wonderful place
where the end of the world
will soon begin.
And thank you again for
the challenge of Homer Simpson.
We've all got
our crosses to bear.
Me Homer. you... the cross.
And now. let me gaze
with reverence
upon the holy
resting place that...
-(snoring)
-(yells)
(mutters):
Uh. wha...?
Homer. this is the
most sacred spot
in Christendom. not
your backyard hammock!
I'm sorry.
It's just that these tours
are so exhausting.
You're jet-lagged.
You're walking around all day.
It's so hard to sleep
knowing Marge and the kids
are all stuck
in one small room. and...
it's so nice and cool
-in the Tomb
of the Unknown Savior.
-Unknown?
This is the tomb of the most
famous man who ever lived!
Porky Pig?
Porky Pig's not a man!
He's a pig. and he's
not even a real pig!
But he is
buried here. right?
That's it!
I'm losing it!
You come all the way
to Jerusalem. the happiest
place on earth.
and all the photos
in your camera are
of funny soda pops?
(groans)
Oh. will you...
You are such a...
Ah!
(chuckles):
Chickpea Fizz!
Delete. Delete. Delete.
Whatever.
It's your camera.
(screams)
(grunts)
(grunting.
thumping)
(grunts)
Please. you've got
to let me back in.
I sold 6.000 rolls
of wrapping paper to get here.
That's your problem.
You. my friend. are banned
from ever entering
this church again.
(slams door)
B-Banned for life?
Homer. do you know
why I'm a Christian?
Your parents made you?
It's because I
believe every soul
has the possibility
of salvation.
At least I thought so
till now.
Homer Simpson.
you are not worth saving.
What? But I thought
we'd be neighbors in Heaven.
-Goofing on all
the new dead people.
-Not...
worth... saving!
HOMER:
Ned! Ned. wait up!
Ned!
(gasps)
Ned's run off into the desert!
Aha!
A sand horse--
car of the desert!
(camel grunting)
Mmm!
Nothing like a tall glass
of lukewarm water
-to Jekyll down this Hyde.
-(wind whooshing)
Ooh. looks like
a sandstorm's brewing.
I'll just wait it out
at a movie.
Orthobot Prime.
the battle begins!
Not so fast--
we can't transform
on the Sabbath!
Let us power down
and contemplate the Torah.
(mechanical whirring)
(robots praying)
(orchestral theme from
Lawrence of Arabia playing)
Flanders!
Stupid Flanders!
(wind whooshing)
(grunting. spitting)
Oh! There's sand
in my shoe! Ooh!
(relieved sighs):
Oh! Oh...!
(camel grunting)
Good luck surviving without me!
(to Lawrence of Arabia theme):
♪ Thirsty ♪
♪ I am so thirsty ♪
♪ And hungry and horny ♪
♪ But mostly just thirsty ♪
♪ I am so thirsty ♪
Huh?
(gasps):
Water!
(hoarsely):
Oh! So salty!
Maybe if I add a little salt.
(dramatic music plays)
(choir vocalizing)
-(thunder rumbling)
-(wind whistling)
(choir vocalizing)
(sobbing)
(sobbing loudly)
You have been chosen. Homer.
Chosen for what.
O mighty gherkin?
Rise and listen. my child.
Yours is
a great destiny.
Pickle. carrot. tomato. pickle.
carrot. tomato. pickle. carrot.
tomato. pickle.
carrot. tomato...
Oh. Homie.
you're alive!
I am more than alive. woman.
I am the Chosen One
who shall unite all the faiths
of the Holy Land!
I am... the Messiah!
But you still have
our passports. right?
Oh. yeah.
Gotta keep track of those.
(shouts):
The Messiah...
(normal voice):
has the passports.
-Dad. are you okay?
-I am more than okay!
I am the Messiah.
come to save the world!
Look upon me and shudder!
I already do that.
Uh... Messiah?
-Do you mind if I have
a word with your wife?
-As you wish.
But look not
upon her with lust.
and do not send her
friendly e-mails.
That's how it begins.
(nervous chuckle)
Homer is suffering
from what's called
"Jerusalem syndrome."
Ah. yes. Jerusalem syndrome:
the name given to religious
delusions or psychoses
that occur when
people visit Jerusalem.
Have you ever noticed that
Dad always gets the disease
they write about in the
in-flight magazine?
MARGE:
Oh. my God!
Homer's gone!
(groans)
What's he gonna do now?
Hmm. Dad said he was going
to unite all faiths.
And only one site is sacred
to Muslims. Christians and Jews:
The Dome of the Rock!
Dome of the Rock?
Messiah away...!
(grunts)
(gasps):
This one says
"Carolina Panthers"!
Messiah says "Rowrr!"
JACOB:
(speaks Hebrew)
Okay. everybody. come on.
This shrine contains the rock
on which Abraham was going
to sacrifice his son.
And Muslims believe
something. too.
To find out. hire
a Muslim tour guide.
That's a barrel
of laughs.
-Anyway. shut your face.
-Thanks. thanks.
You can stop
giving the tour now.
You don't want to
do a photo with me?
You can hold my gun.
-I used it in Entebbe.
I killed three Ugandans.
-No. thanks.
Before you go in.
you fill out
comment card.
(groans):
Okay.
Uh. eh. don't
forget the back.
You people are so pushy.
What. Israeli
people are pushy?
How about you experience
a couple of genocides
and see how laid-back
you are?
We were purged from Spain!
Throw out of there!
They allow everybody in Spain!
But for us. Jews.
no flamenco. get out!
I'm pushy? Please.
You stay there.
surrounded by your
great enemy. Canada!
Try Syria for two months.
then we'll see who's pushy!
Attention. Christians.
Muslims. and Jews:
I have come to gather you
into a new faith.
From now on.
you shall be called...
Chris-mu-jews.
-(unenthusiastic murmuring)
-MAN: I-I don't know.
Because when you get down to it.
aren't all religions the same?
They tell you
what to eat.
when to pray.
how this imperfect clay
that we call man
can mold itself
to resemble the divine.
But we can never attain
that ultimate grace
while there is hatred in
our hearts for each other.
(quietly):
I did it.
I reached him.
Celebrate your commonality.
Some of us don't eat pork.
Some of us don't eat shellfish.
But all of us love chicken.
-(excited murmuring)
-MAN: He's right!
You can simmer
it in a tagine.
In a soup. you can boil it!
Spread the word!
Peace and chicken.
CROWD:
Peace and chicken!
Don't listen to this fat idiot!
I am your Messiah!
Avert your eyes
from my wrinkly arms!
Uh-oh. Got another case
of Jerusalem syndrome.
This looks like a job for...
the Messiah!
(sighs)
(overlapping chatter)
I want the window seat!
Krav maga!
You can't hurt
what's already dead.
-(grunts)
-(groans): I guess you can.
Homer. my friend. of all
the false messiahs today.
I think you came
closest to the truth.
Well. if I made
any sense today.
it's because all the stuff
you've told me all these years
has finally seeped in.
Can I buy you
a $12 turkey sandwich?
I'd like that.
How about a Greg Norman
Executive Putter
-from the SkyMall?
-You'd probably
get a better deal
at a mall back home.
They have malls on land?
♪♪
JACOB:
Why don't you try
having your people
being thrown out of Spain?
Spain! No tapas!
I love eating tapas!
I love the tiny portions!
You don't get too full.
but you have a whole variety
of flavors!
Not for me!
Every day hummus and pita!
Occasionally. once a week.
a little bit of falafel!
♪♪
L'chaim!
Enhanced by Fotokem